A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Half Pay Claims for the Revolutionary War, 1783-1851
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Half Pay Claims for the Revolutionary War, 1783-1851
The Library of Virginia
APA 203
.90 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts (1776-1928)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Auditor of Public Accounts in 1913.
Biographical Information
During its session begun in May 1779 the General Assembly granted half pay for life to officers who served to the end of the revolutionary war, or who, if their unit was reorganized, were thereby rendered supernumerary officers subject to recall. In 1780 the General Assembly granted half pay for seven years to the widows and orphans of officers. Virginia defaulted on its half pay cliams, however, and by an act of Congress passed 5 July 1832 the United States government assumed these obligations.
Scope and Content
Records, 1783-1851, including accounts, claims, correspondence, and reports relating to half pay granted to Virginia officers who served in the Revolutionary War. The claims contain copies of court records that often include the name of heirs and the service record of the soldier. Some claims also include copies of wills, powers of attorney, bonds, judgements, and statements proving the claims. The claims are a good source of genealogical information and are listed alphabetically. The correspondence, 1831-1833, are another good source of information as they often relate to specific claims by soldiers. The correspondence is mainly between Louis McLane, U.S. Secretary of the Treasury, and James E. Heath, Auditor of Virginia, regarding claims and providing background of various claims. Also included are reports, 1832-1851, listing names of soldiers whose claims were settled or paid out.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Accounts, 1833-1834 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Claims: Armistead, William [Also: Campbell, Wiilliam; Savage, Nathaniel S.; Tinsley, Samuel; Russell, John; Hoffler, William; Brough, Robert, and Digges, Dudley], 1791 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Claims: Banks, Henry, 1795-1798 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Claims: Barron, Richard, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Claims: Boush, Robert, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Claims: Brodie, Ludowick, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Claims: Brown, Windsor, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Claims: Carter, Thomas, 1792-1794 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Claims: Clark, George Rogers, 1833, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Claims: Coleman, Wyatt, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Claims: Cowne, Robert, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Claims: Crockett, Joseph, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Claims: Crump, Abner, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Claims: Dalton, Valentine Thomas, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Claims: Davenport, Opea, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Claims: Digges, Dudley, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Claims: Dixon, Anthony T., 1830-1833 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Claims: Ewell, Thomas Winder, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Claims: Forsythe, Robert, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Claims: Fox, Nathaniel, 1797 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Claims: Galt, John Minson, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Claims: George, Robert, 1835-1847 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Claims: Gibbs, Churchill, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Claims: Gibson, George, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Claims: Girault, John, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Claims: Graham, Walter, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Claims: Graves, Ralph, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Claims: Graves, William, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Claims: Creer, Charles, 1833-1846 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Claims: Harper, James, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Claims: Herbert, Thomas, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Claims: Hoffler, William, 1792-1794, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Claims: Hudson, John, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Claims: Hughes, Pratt [Also Roane, Christopher and Thompson, William], 1791-1793 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Claims: Johnston, Gideon, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Claims: Kautzman, John V., 1791 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Claims: Kemp, Peter, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Claims: Kerney, John, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Claims: Lipscomb, Yancey, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Claims: Livingston, Judge, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- McClurg, James [Also Dixon, Anthony], 1791 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Magill, Charles, 1783, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Claims: Mann, David, 1791-1792 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Claims: Markham, James, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Claims: Marshall, James Markham, 1833, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Claims: Marshall, Thomas, Jr. and Sr., 1833 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Claims: Marston, John, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Claims: Maupin, Gabriel, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Claims: Meriwether, James, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Claims: Meriwether, Thomas, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Claims: Montgomery, John, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Claims: Moore, Peter, 1843, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Claims: Murray, William, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Claims: Muter, George, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Claims: Oliver, William, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Claims: Quarles, James, 1792-1794 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Claims: Quarles, Thomas, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Claims: Quarles, William, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Claims: Quirk, Thomas [Also Quarles, Thomas], 1791-1792 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Claims: Rice, Nathaniel, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Claims: Roberts, Benjamin, 1833, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Claims: Saunders, Joseph, 1833, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Claims: Scott, Walter, 1783 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Claims: Slaughter, George, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Claims: Slaughter, William, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Claims: Spencer, John, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Claims: Spiller, William, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Claims: Thompson, William, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Claims: Thruston, John, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Claims: Tinsley, Samuel, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Claims: Todd, Robert, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Claims: Turner, John, 1792, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Claims: Valentine, Jacob, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Claims: Vaughn, John, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Claims: Vawler, William [Also Williams, John and Woodson, Frederick], 1791 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Claims: Vogleson, Amand, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Claims: Voules, Henry, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Claims: Walls, George, 1833-1836 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Claims: Walls, Thomas, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Claims: Warnick, Frederick, 1792-1796 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Claims: White, William, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Claims: Wiatt, Cary, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Claims: Williams, Jarret, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Claims: Young, Thomas, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, 1832 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, 1833 January-February (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, 1833 March-September (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Reports of payments of Half Pay Claims, 1832-1851 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Wrappers and fragments, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)